Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Moving Images Collection FILMS.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I. Transport Workers Union of America Films, 1930-1977; 34.5 Linear Feet in 16 record cartons and 177 film cans; 13.3 Gigabytes in 18 digital files
  - Subseries I.A. Films, 1930-1977
    - Negotiations with NYCTA, 1965 (Film canister c148, 16mm film reels 001_0220)
      Negotiations between the Transport Workers Union and the New York City Transit Authority prior to 1966 transit strike; press conferences given by both sides and by arbitrators.
    - Transit Strike Interviews, Michael Quill's Funeral, 1965-1966 (Box 22, 16mm film reels 001_0899)
      Interviews with some of the first passengers to ride the subways and some of first transit workers to return to work after 1966 New York City transit strike; press conference with Michael Quill; Quill's funeral.
    - Airport Clips, 1967 (Box 34, 16mm film reels 001_0268)
      Airport baggage and baggage handlers; airplane maintenance mechanics; jet and propeller airplanes and helicopters.
    - Subway and Airport Footage, 1967 (Box 34, 16mm film reels 001_0275)
      See the video reproduction cuid37014 in Subseries I.B.
      Elevated subway trains and New York City landscapes shot from elevated subway trains; subway train repair shop; airport baggage handlers.
    - Annacond Demonstration, March, 1968 (Box 11, Super 8mm film reel 001_0613)
    - American Postal Workers Union Picketing, New Orleans, August 16, 1972 (Film canister c193, 16mm film reels 001_0062)
      Solidarity demonstration for the Farah strikers by the American Postal Workers Union during an APWU national convention in New Orleans.
    - Reform At Last!, 1977 (Film canister c243, 16mm film reels 001_0789)
      Documentary advocating for the Taft-Hartley Act and the Landrum-Griffin amendments to the Wagner Act. It discusses the current labor situation in which large companies in the textile, auto parts, and steel industries flout the labor laws with impunity, exploiting workers. Most of the film consists of voiceover narration over still photographs, drawings, and graphics. Live-action footage includes clips of George Meany speaking at a meeting.
    - Airplane Maintenance and Bus Strike Footage, Undated (Box 19, Film canister c108, 16mm film reels 001_0415)
      Airplane maintenance; Transport Workers Union strikers picket.
    - Airplane and Subway Clips, Undated (Film canister c214, 16mm film reels 001_0166)
    - Airplane and Subway Footage, Undated (Film canister c181, 16mm film reels 001_0327)
      A few different shots of a jet airplane aloft and of subway trains.
    - Airport Trims, Undated (Box 32, 16mm film reels 001_0883, 001_0881, 001_0886, 001_0885, 001_0884, Box 30, 16mm film reels 001_0878, 001_0880, 001_0882, 001_0879, 001_0877, 001_0876)
    - Footage of Industrial Equipment, Undated (Film canister c110, 16mm film reels 001_0351)
      Control rooms, turbines, interiors and exteriors of industrial buildings.
    - John Quill Applauding, Undated (Box 32, 16mm film reels 001_0316)
      John Quill is the son of Michael Quill.
    - TWU -- Man and Small Boy, Undated (Box 16, Film canister c128, 16mm film reels 001_0389)
    - Michael Quill on Indictment, Undated (Film canister c170, 16mm film reels 001_0198)
      Transport Workers Union's Michael Quill responds to an indictment by Brooklyn District Attorney.
    - Michael Quill Speaks, Undated (Film canister c166, 16mm film reels 001_0205)
    - Negotiations Between TWU and NYCTA, Undated (Film canister c116, 16mm film reels 001_0338)
      This film includes 1) A joint press conference by the Transport Workers Union and the New York City Transit Authority to report on negotiations between the two parties. John O'Donnell, Matthew Guinan, and Michael Quill are present. 2) An open arbitration session between the TWU and NYCTA, including Theodore Kheel. Duplicate of 001_0337.
    - Pennsylvania Railroad Strike Announcement, Undated (Film canister c158, 16mm film reels 001_0746)
      Five takes of an announcement by Michael Quill. He was accompanied by Eugene Attreed and Frank Sheehan. Quill announces a strike by the Transport Workers Union against the Pennsylvania Railroad; he says negotiations are deadlocked and that the union is asking its members to commence strike at "one minute after midnight."
    - Philip Murray Speaks, Undated (Film canister c235, 16mm film reels 001_0033)
    - Press Conference on NYCTA Collective Bargaining, Undated (Film canister c115, 16mm film reels 001_0238)
    - Transportation - Gateway to the Future Title, Undated (Film canister c214, 16mm film reels 001_0167)
    - Trims, Undated (Film canister c236, 16mm film reels 001_0034, 001_0035, 001_0036, 001_0037, 001_0038, 001_0039, 001_0040, 001_0041, 001_0042, 16mm film reels 001_0043, 001_0044, 001_0045, 001_0046, 001_0047, 001_0048, 001_0049, 001_0050, 001_0051, 001_0052)
      Trims including: IBC Meeting; Josie Lynch; street scenes; shop worker; bus operations; MacMahon interview. These may be trims from the film The Best is Yet to Come.
    - TWU and Michael Quill Photographs, Undated (Film canister c235, 16mm film reels 001_0028)
      Still photographs relating to Transport Workers Union and Michael Quill
    - William O'Dwyer Speaks, Undated (Film canister c96, 16mm film reels 001_0334)
      Former New York City mayor William O'Dwyer speaks out in favor of organizing civil service workers.
  - Subseries I.B. Video Reproductions, 1930-1967
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Broadcast Master Tape 1, 1930-1949; cuid36982 (Box 2, Betacam sp cuid36982)
      Includes the following clips: Transport Workers Union members leafleting on street at parade; Transport Workers Union bus drivers; Transport Workers Union's Transport Hall; Philip Murray negotiates with New York City mayor, City Hall, New York, NY; Transport Workers Union rally at City Hall; Exterior of bus company garage; 1930s street scenes in New York City boroughs; Transport Workers Union elections; Early demonstration by Transport Workers Union; early footage of some of union's founding member leaders speaking at a rally.
      Transfer from film; Duration: 25 minutes
    - Broadcast Master Tape 2, 1930-1949; cuid914 (Box 14, Betacam sp cuid914)
      Includes the following clips: Transport Workers Union members picket the homes of former dozen TWU members; Michael Quill and other union leaders speak at outdoor rallies; Rally for Michael Quill's re-election to New York City Council; Third Biennial Convention of the Transport Workers Union; Transport Workers Union and pro-World War II demonstrations; field days and outings of the Transport Workers Union's members and families.
      Transfer from film; Estimated Duration: 00:59:35
    - Broadcast Master Tape 3, 1940-1969; cuid1024 (Box 2, Betacam sp cuid1024)
      Includes the following clips: Transport Workers Union strikers' picket line; Transport Workers Union pickets homes of ex-members; Airplane maintenance; airplane baggage; flight crew and United We Are Invincible documentary; Bus drivers' occupational maladies; Transport Workers Union strike meeting; Bus-driving, bus passengers, and traffic in New York City; CIO Convention in Philadelphia, PA; Local 100 delegates departing New York City for TWU 6th Biennial Convention; Michael Quill and his young son, John, at a Transport Workers Union convention.
      Transfer from film; Estimated Duration: 01:00:35
    - Broadcast Master Tape 4, 1940-1949; cuid36983 (Box 2, Betacam sp cuid36983)
      Includes the following clips: Transport Workers Union officers, staff, and families at a celebration; Scenes from Transport Workers Union's 6th Biennial Convention, Chicago, IL; Demonstration; Fiorello LaGuardia and Michael Quill speaking at a rally; Demonstrations, picket lines, rallies of Transport Workers Union urging New York City's Board of Transportation to implement collective bargaining.
      Transfer from film; Duration: 23 minutes
    - Broadcast Master Tape 5, 1950; cuid36984 (Box 2, Betacam sp cuid36984)
      Includes part of the documentary film Our Case For The Forty-Hour Week.
      Transfer from film; Duration: 46 minutes
    - Broadcast Master Tape 6, 1950-1951; cuid36985 (Box 2, Betacam sp cuid36985)
      Includes the following clips: Seventh Biennial TWU Convention proceedings; Local 100 members voting.
      Transfer from film; Duration: 49 minutes
    - Broadcast Master Tape 7, 1951; cuid36986 (Box 2, Betacam sp cuid36986)
      Includes the following clips: Contract negotiations between Transport Workers Union and New York City private bus lines.
      Film transfer; Duration: 44 minutes
    - Broadcast Master Tape 8, 1952-1953; cuid36987 (Box 2, Betacam sp cuid36987)
      Includes the following clips: Television program relating to Transport Workers Union's 1952 convention, Philadelphia, PA; Memorial meeting for Philip Murray; Twenty-Nine Days To Victory documentary.
      Film transfer; Duration: 61 minutes
    - Broadcast Master Tape 9, 1950-1959; cuid36988 (Box 2, Betacam sp cuid36988)
      Includes the following clips: Michael Quill and Matthew Guinan at a Transport Workers Union mass meeting on the eve of the 1953 private bus lines strike in New York City; Quill and Allan Haywood address mass strike meeting; Rank and file members at TWU meeting; Allan Haywood and Michael Quill addressing mass meeting; workers going on and coming off shifts; Press release of Michael Quill announcing a meeting of striking bus workers; Allan Haywood of the CIO speaks in support of New York City bus strike and need for 40-hour week for New York City and Philadelphia bus drivers; Father Charles Owen Rice making a statement of support for a Transport Workers Union strike.
      Film transfer; Duration: 50 minutes
    - Broadcast Master Tape 10, 1953; cuid36989 (Box 3, Betacam sp cuid36989)
      Includes the following clips: Officers of the Transport Workers Union report on the progress of the 1953 strike against New York City private bus lines; Michael Quill addresses two different mass meetings during 1953 strike against private bus lines.
      Transfer from film; Duration: 53 minutes
    - Broadcast Master Tape 11, 1953; cuid36990 (Box 2, Betacam sp cuid36990)
      Includes the following clips: Mass meeting of strikers during Transport Workers Union's 1953 strike against New York City private bus lines; Crowded subway station and subway station entrances.
      Transfer from film; Durartion: 52 minutes
    - Broadcast Master Tape 12, 1952-1953; cuid36991 (Box 2, Betacam sp cuid36991)
      Includes the following clips: Memorial Tribute to Allan S. Haywood; Matthew Guinan, Ellis Van Riper, John O'Donnell and Michael Quill report to mass meeting of Local 100 members on relations with the New York City Transit Authority.
      Transfer from film; Duration: 43 minutes
    - Broadcast Master Tape 13, 1953; cuid1025 (Box 2, Betacam sp cuid1025)
      Includes the following clips: Last official meeting at TWU's old headquarters; Commemoration of the union's history and opening of its new headquarters; TWU members voting.
      Transfer from film; Estimated Duration: 00:51:25
    - Broadcast Master Tape 14, 1953-1962; cuid1026 (Box 2, Betacam sp cuid1026)
      Includes the following clips: Michael Quill speaks at mass meeting; Michael Quill makes a statement endorsing Robert F. Wagner, Jr. for mayor of New York; Exteriors of co-op apartment buildings, New York City school; footage relating to Robert F. Wagner, Jr.'s mayoral election campaign; Michael Quill addressing mass meeting of Local 100 members on strike; 20th Anniversary Celebration of the Transport Workers Union.
      Transfer from film; Estimated Duration: 01:02:00
    - Broadcast Master Tape 15, 1950-1959; cuid36992 (Box 3, Betacam sp cuid36992)
      Includes the following clips: 20th Anniversary Celebration of the Transport Workers Union; Two press conferences with Michael Quill speaking; passengers on New York City subway trains and buses; Transport Workers Union's Twentieth Anniversary Meeting.
      Transfer from film; Duration: 57 minutes
    - Broadcast Master Tape 16, 1954-1957; cuid36993 (Box 3, Betacam sp cuid36993)
      Includes the following clips: Transport Workers Union demonstration to save the Third Avenue elevated subway line in New York City; Officers of Local 234 and Michael Quill urge local members to ratify new contract with Philadelphia Transportation Company; Partial print of the film A Memorial Tribute To Philip Murray.
      Transfer from film; Duration: 63 minutes
    - Broadcast Master Tape 17, 1950-1959; cuid1027 (Box 14, Betacam sp cuid1027)
      Includes the following clips: Segments from the film A Memorial Tribute To Philip Murray; Michael Quill statement on progress of American labor; Michael Quill demands that the New York City Transit Authority conduct a representation election among its employees; Local 100 members vote to authorize a strike against private bus lines; demonstration and automobile cavalcade against the Pennsylvania Railroad; TWU officials present the union's complaints against the management of the Pennsylvania Railroad to a meeting of presidents of 51 Railroad Division locals; Michael Quill reacts to an indictment handed down by a Brooklyn Grand Jury; Local 100 mass meeting.
      Transfer from film; Estimated Duration: 01:03:22
    - Broadcast Master Tape 18, 1959-1960; cuid36994 (Box 3, Betacam sp cuid36994)
      Includes the following clips: Harry Van Arsdale, Jr. addresses a Local 100 mass meeting; Michael Quill press conference announcing a contract proposal for the New York City Transit Authority; New York City Transit Authority strike meeting; press conference with Michael Quill criticizing New York City Transit Authority's deal with the Consolidated Edison company; airline merger opposition announcement; Press conference on wildcat bus driver strike.
    - Broadcast Master Tape 19, 1950-1961; cuid36995 (Box 1, Betacam sp cuid36995)
      Includes the following clips: Robert F. Wagner, Jr. delivers a primary election campaign speech at a TWU meeting; labor union banquet and award ceremony; TWU picket line and mass rally; press conferences held by Michael Quill and other TWU leaders; interview with Senator Wayne Morse; Press conference by Michael Quill on union's demands to New York City Board of Transportation or New York City Transit Authority; Michael Quill and other officers negotiating with the New York City Transit Authority; Leaflet distribution; Michael Quill at press conference.
      Transfer from film; Duration: 59 minutes
    - Broadcast Master Tape 20, 1950-1965; cuid1028 (Box 1, Betacam sp cuid1028)
      Includes the following clips: Buses and passengers in mid-town Manhattan; Santa Claus promotes public transportation; Michael Quill announces end of a wildcat strike by Philadelphia TWU workers; Special counsel Arthur Goldberg's statement on TWU representation of New York City transit workers; Local 100 party; Trims and outtakes from a number of different films or shoots, including footage from a New York City mayoral campaign film, a TWU demonstration, and shots of New Yorkers' feet; Michael Quill announces that a bus strike has been called off.
      Transfer from film; Estimated Duration: 00:45:57
    - Broadcast Master Tape 21, 1950-1969; cuid36996 (Box 1, Betacam sp cuid36996)
      Includes the following clips: Mixed trims and outtakes; shots of street signs in New York City; TWU mass meetings; press conferences by Michael Quill; pickets against the Pennsylvania Railroad; address by Michael Quill to members; Michael Quill answers questions about a threatened strike against the Pennsylvania and New York Central Railroad; Why Pennsylvania Railroad Strike? television program.
      Transfer from film; Duration: 50 minutes
    - Broadcast Master Tape 22, 1960-1961; cuid36997 (Box 1, Betacam sp cuid36997)
      Includes the following clips: New York City Labor Day parades of 1960 and 1961; TWU strike against the Philadelphia Transit Company, Philadelphia, PA.
    - Broadcast Master Tape 23, 1961; cuid36998 (Box 5, Betacam sp cuid36998)
      Includes the following clips: Reports to membership of Local 234; Television broadcast by the Transport Workers Union to its membership on its new contract with the Philadelphia Transit Company; Matthew Guinan and Ellis Van Riper speak at joint Executive Committee meeting.
      Transfer from film; Duration: 56 minutes
    - Broadcast Master Tape 24, 1961; cuid36999 (Box 5, Betacam sp cuid36999)
      Transfer from film; Duration: 48 minutes
      Includes the following clips: Trims of members speaking from floor at TWU meeting; Union officers addressing same meeting off-screen; TWU meeting discussing formation of a labor party and endorsing Robert F. Wagner, Jr.; Robert F. Wagner, Jr. at TWU meeting.
    - Broadcast Master Tape 25, 1959-1961; cuid37000 (Box 5, Betacam sp cuid37000)
      Includes the following clips: Candidates for mayor, comptroller and president of city council in New York City election address TWU meeting; NYC Labor Day Parade 1961; Jimmy Hoffa speaks at Transport Workers Union's 11th Biennial convention; Years Of Challenge documentary.
    - Broadcast Master Tape 26, 1959-1961; cuid37001 (Box 5, Betacam sp cuid37001)
      Includes the following clips: Years Of Challenge documentary (partial soundtrack, but superior visual quality); Union leaders speak at mass meeting; Audience shots at mass meeting; Picket signs at mass meeting.
      Transfer from film; Duration: 62 minutes
    - Broadcast Master Tape 27, 1961; cuid37002 (Box 5, Betacam sp cuid37002)
      Includes the following clips: Michael Quill addresses mass meeting; Matthew Guinan addresses mass meeting; Brooklyn Union Gas Company strike picket line and rally; Press conference on strike against the Brooklyn Union Gas Company; officers entering Gracie Mansion (mayor of New York's official residence); official reports on progress of negotiations with Brooklyn Union Gas officials.
      Transfer from film; Duration: 61 minutes
    - Broadcast Master Tape 28, 1961-1962; cuid37003 (Box 5, Betacam sp cuid37003)
      Includes the following clips: leaders address TWU mass meeting on subject of attempted corporate takeover of Fifth Avenue Coach Company; Michael Quill announcing strike against New York City's private bus lines; Michael Quill announces union's intention to become actively involved in the stockholder struggle over the Fifth Avenue Coach Company.
      Transfer from film; Duration: 38 minutes
    - Broadcast Master Tape 29, 1961-1962; cuid37004 (Box 5, Betacam sp cuid37004)
      Includes the following clips: proposal to membership on how to combat a corporate takeover of the Fifth Avenue Coach Company; Arbitration hearing before Theodore Kheel on the insolvency of the Fifth Avenue Coach Company.
    - Broadcast Master Tape 30, February 21, 1962; cuid37005 (Box 1, Betacam sp cuid37005)
      Emergency mass meeting called by Local 100 to vote on resolution to strike against the Fifth Avenue Coach Company.
      Transfer from film; Duration: 36 minutes
    - Broadcast Master Tape 31, 1962; cuid37006 (Box 1, Betacam sp cuid37006)
      Includes the following clips: Lobbying trip to New York State Legislature by strikers during strike against Fifth Avenue Coach Company; Fifth Avenue Coach Company strike victory meeting; TWU participation in New York City St. Patrick's Day parade; Michael Quill's rebuttal on WCBS-TV to Roy Cohn and Lawrence Weissman's televised statements about the TWU's strike against the Fifth Avenue Coach Company.
    - Broadcast Master Tape 32, 1962; cuid37007 (Box 1, Betacam sp cuid37007)
      Includes the following clips: Mass meeting of TWU strikers against Fifth Avenue Coach Company; TWU delegation in New York City St. Patrick's Day parade; TWU strike picket line against Fifth Avenue Coach Company; Fifth Avenue Coach Company strikers picket New York Governor Nelson Rockefeller's offices.
      Transfer from film; Duration: 60 minutes
    - Broadcast Master Tape 33, 1962; cuid37008 (Box 1, Betacam sp cuid37008)
      Includes the following clips: Picket lines, rallies, meetings during strike against the Fifth Avenue Coach Company; Fifth Avenue Coach Company pensioners in wheelchairs being helped on and off buses; picket line by pensioners of the Fifth Avenue Coach Company; Stockholders' meeting of Fifth Avenue Coach Company; pickets in front of Biltmore Hotel; pickets at the headquarters of the Fifth Avenue Coach Company; Matthew Guinan speaks at picket line at Fifth Avenue Coach Company headquarters; Michael Quill announces end of strike by workers on the New York City Omnibus and Third Avenue bus systems; Victory demonstration by strikers against the Fifth Avenue Coach Company; workers in bus repair shop.
      Transfer from film; Duration: 64 minutes
    - Broadcast Master Tape 34, 1962-1964; cuid37009 (Box 1, Betacam sp cuid37009)
      Includes the following clips: Signing of 1964/65 contract between Transport Workers Union and the New York City Transit Authority; press conference following the signing; report on this contract by union officers; Mayor Robert F. Wagner, Jr. reports to press on his discussions with Transport Workers Union officials, New York City Transit Authority officials and mediators on contract negotiations; Michael Quill discussing breakdown of negotiations with New York Transit Authority and threatened strike; Press conference following statement by Michael Quill proposing nationalization of the nation's railroads.
    - Broadcast Master Tape 35, 1964; cuid1029 (Box 1, Betacam sp cuid1029)
      Transport Workers Union 30th Anniversary Convention, Americana Hotel, New York, NY
      Transfer from film; Estimated Duration: 01:00:00, BW
    - Broadcast Master Tape 36, 1964-1966; cuid1030 (Box 1, Betacam sp cuid1030)
      Includes the following clips: Michael Quill announces signing of contract between union and Pennsylvania Railroad; Press conference on contract negotiations between Transport Workers Union and New York City Transit Authority; New York City Transit strike; location shots of San Francisco; gas storage tank; Michael Quill's funeral service at St. Patrick's Cathedral.
      Transfer from film; Estimated Duration: 00:26:00
    - Broadcast Master Tape 37, 1941-1969; cuid37010 (Box 1, Betacam sp cuid37010)
      Includes the following clips: Pan American Airways airplane repair shops; Subway tunnels; subway station platforms; Fashion show; John Quill applauding; negotiating session between union officials and management; Sequences and outtakes from documentary United We Are Invincible; Interior shots of a New York City powerhouse facility; Trains; train passengers; unemployed workers; statements by both union and management on strike against the Pennsylvania Railroad.
    - Broadcast Master Tape 38, 1950-1961; cuid37011 (Box 3, Betacam sp cuid37011)
      Includes the following clips: Deserted waterfront, train station, trains, and train yards; Transport Workers Union's participation in 1960 New York City Labor Day Parade; Exterior and interior shots of a New York City powerhouse facility; Events leading up to Transport Workers Union 1961 strike against the Philadelphia Transportation Company.
    - Broadcast Master Tape 39, 1961-1962; cuid37012 (Box 3, Betacam sp cuid37012)
      Includes the following clips: negotiations between the Transport Workers Union Local 234 and the Philadelphia Transportation Company; 1961 Labor Day Parade, New York, NY; Lobbying trip to Albany, New York by striking New York City bus drivers.
    - Broadcast Master Tape 40, 1930-1966; cuid1031 (Box 14, Betacam sp cuid1031)